When working with Word documents,
there may be occasions you wish to
password protect the document, so that
only yourself and and others who are
allowed access, can open the file.
This may be because it contains
sensitive or personal information.
To add protection to a document,
you first open the document and then
simply navigate up to the file menu.
And from there select info, and once
you've selected info you will click
on the protect document button.
This will give you a number of options
of how you can protect the document.
The two we are going to
look at are encrypt with
password and restrict editing.
So if I click on the encrypt with
password, it will then bring up the
password dialog box and I will create
the password, select OK, and again,
it will ask for this to be entered
twice just to ensure it's correct.
Click OK.
And that has now protected the document.
That protection won't be applied
until I select save, so if I
saved it now, it will protect it.
But if I close the document and didn't
save it, it would still be unprotected.
So I click save and
then close the document.
The next time I go to open the
document, it will ask for a
password, enter the password, and
that will then open the document.
If at a point in the future, I wish to
remove the password, I would quite simply
go to file, info, protect document,
encrypt with password, and then remove
the password, leave it blank, select OK.
And as you can see, that
has now gone back to normal.
Again, if I don't save that, the
password will still be active, so I
need to click save and close that now.
And then when I open it again, it will
simply open without asking for a password.
There may be occasions when, rather than
adding a password, you may just restrict
the editing of the document so that people
can read it, but they can't make any
changes such as add more text or delete
information contained within the document.
Again, to do this, you can add
protection so that the file is read only.
So if you go to File and then
info and on the protect document
dropdown, select restrict editing.
And this will open up the restrict
editing dialogue box to the right.
So what you're looking for in here is
to ensure that the editing restrictions
are applied as "no changes read only".
Later in the course, you will be required
to create some forms where you will need
to select filling in forms, but in this
instance, to purely protect the document
from any changes, I need to make sure that
no changes, read only is selected and then
select yes, start enforcing protection.
Now again, if I don't put a password in
here, then people will be able to go into
the editing restrictions and make changes.
So if I just add a password and
reenter to confirm, select OK,
and then that is now protected.
So if I close that and I try and
make any changes it won't allow me.
It will give the box up
so there's a warning.
So this document is protected from
unintentional editing, you may
only view this region and there
are no regions that can be edited.
They could click on stop protection, but
they would need the password to be able
to make any changes to the document.
And every time they type in,
they would make it try to make
a change, nothing will happen.